Mss.974.8.D65 Mss.974.8.D65
American Philosophical Society
Documents, 1728-1816, relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution
Mss.974.8.D65
American Philosophical Society
1.0 volume, 50 p.
This volume includes messages and proclamations of governors of the province, a petition to the King from the province of Georgia [n.d.], the draft of an address of the University of the State of Pennsylvania to George Washington (1781), a letter from Arthur Lee to Alexander Wedderburn (1774), letters of Timothy Matlack to Abiel Holmes (1819), and George Wythe's draft resolutions (1775).
1 volume, 50 p.
Holmes, Abiel, 1763-1837
Lee, Arthur, 1740-1792
Matlack, Timothy, 1736-1829
Various authors
Volume 1
Early American History Note
This volume contains documents that relate to the government of Pennsylvania. Although the volume is described in MOLE as pertaining to the American Revolution in Pennsylvania, the volume begins with a proclamation from 1728 and contains a range of proclamations from the Seven Years’ War, before ending with a series of proclamations from the 1770s and 1780s. Although there are some lists and petitionsand orders in the volume, almost all of the documents are official government proclamations, often from the governor. The revolutionary era documents are a bit more diverse. In addition to official government documents, such as militia instructions, the volume contains manuscript copies of letters and essays intended for print, as well as private correspondence and messages from other colonies.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Received and accessioned, 1913 (1911 47041).
General note
An index to the manuscripts (3 p.) is included in the volume.
Washington, George, 1732-1799; Wedderburn, Alexander; Wythe, George, 1726-1806; American Revolution; Colonial Politics; Georgia -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775.; Government Affairs; Official Government Documents and Records; Pennsylvania -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775.; Pennsylvania -- Politics and government -- To 1775.; Pennsylvania History; Petitions.; Proclamations.; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Personal histories.
- Papers
  - Instructions to the governments of New York, 1728; 974.8 D65. 1; Great Britain. Sovereign (1727-1760: George II)
    Scope and Contents note
    New Jersey, Pennsylvania and Connecticut, for the suppression of piracy. 15p. F. Lond. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution, no. 1) Manuscript.
  - Proclamation laying an embargo on provisions and war stores., 1755; 974.8 D65. 10; Pennsylvania (Colony) Governor - Morris, Robert Hunter
    1p. F. Phil. (in Documents relating to the provice of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 10) Manuscript.
  - Proclamation laying an embargo on all shipping., 1757; 974.8 D65. 11; Pennsylvania (Colony) Governor - Denny, William
    1p. F. New Castle, (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 11) Manuscript.
  - Petition to the Assembly of Pennsylvania., 1755; 974.8 D65. 12; Menunist church in Lancaster
    2p. F. Lancaster, (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 12) Manuscript.
  - From Col. John Stanwix to the commander of his majesty's forces at New Castle., 1757; 974.8 D65. 16; Stanwix, John, 1690?-1766
    1p. F. Phil. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 16) Manuscript.
  - From Richard Peters to William Till, 1757; 974.8 D65. 17; Peters, Richard, 1704-1776
    collector of customs at New Castle. 1p. F. n.p. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 17) Manuscript.
  - [Letter] From Gov. James Hamilton to William Till., 1760; 974.8 D65. 18; Pennsylvania (Colony) Governor - Hamilton, James
    4p. F. New Castle, (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 18) Manuscript.
  - From William Till to Gov., 1760; 974.8 D65. 19; Till, William
    James Hamilton. 2p. F. New Castle, (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. no. 19) Manuscript.
  - From Lord Egremont to the governor of Pennsylvania., 1763; 974.8 D65. 21; Pennsylvania (Colony) Governor - Hamilton, James
    3p. F. Whitehall, (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 20) Manuscript.
  - From the Commissioners of the customs to William Till., 1763; 974.8 D65. 22; Great Britain - Commissioners of the customs
    2p. F. Lond. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 22) Manuscript. Dup. no.23
  - From Lord Egrement to the governor of Pennsylvania., 1763; 974.8 D65. 22; Egremont, Charles Wyndham, Earl of, 1710-1763
    3p. F. Whitehall, (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. no.20) Manuscript. Dup.no.21
  - From the Commissioners of the customs to William Till., 1763; 974.8 D65. 24; Great Britain - Commissioners of the customs
    2p. F. Lond. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 24) Manuscript.
  - From the Commissioners of the customs to William Till., 1764; 974.8 D65. 25; Great Britain - Commissioners of the customs
    2p. F. Lond. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. No. 25) Manuscript
  - Circular letter of Gilbert Tennent, 1764; 974.8 D65. 26; Ewing, John, 1732-1802 others
    Francis Alison and John Ewing, relating to making Pennsylvania a royal province. 2p. F. Phil. (in documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. no.26) Manuscript.
  - Pardon granted to Anne Jew by Gov. Penn., 1766; 974.8 D65. 27; Pennsylvania (Colony) Proprietary governor - Penn, John
    1 p. F. phil. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. No. 27) Manuscript.
  - From Arthur Lee to Alexander Wedderburn., 1774; 974.8 D65. 31; Lee, Arthur, 1740-1792
    1 p. F. n.p. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. No. 31) Manuscript.
  - Petition to the king to withdraw troops and fleets from our shores., Undated; 974.8 D65. 32; Georgia (Colony) - Assembly
    2p. F. n.P. n.d. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. no.32.) Manuscript.
  - From Samuel Purviance, jr. to William Bradford., 1774; 974.8 D65. 34; Purviance, Samuel, jr.
    1 p. F. Baltimore, (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. No. 34) Manuscript.
  - From Nathaniel Coffin to John Paterson., 1775; 974.8 D65. 35; Coffin, Nathaniel
    3p. F. Boston, (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 35.) Manuscript.
  - From Edward Burd to James Burd., 1775; 974.8 D65. 36; Burd, Edward, 1751-1833
    3p. F. Cambridge, (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. No. 36) Manuscript.
  - Message to the assembly of Pennsylvania., 1756; 974.8 D65. 4; Pennsylvania (Colony) Governor - Denny, William
    1p. F. Phil. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 4.) Manuscript.
  - Circular letter from Thomas Wharton, jr., 1777; 974.8 D65. 41; Wharton, Thomas, 1730-1782
    President of the Supreme executive council of Pennsylvania, in reference to disarming the loyalists. 2p. F. Phil. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. no.41.) Manuscript.
  - Congratulatory address to Gen. Washington by the Trustees of the University of Pennsylvania., 1781; 974.8 D65. 42; University of Pennsylvania. Trustees
    2p. F. [Phil.] (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. No. 42.) Manuscript.
  - Letter to Matthew Carey, March 15, 1785; 974.8 D65. 47; 8" x 12 3/4"; Washington, George, 1732-1799
    Mount Vernon, Facsimile of A.L.S. 1p. Relates to the delivery of his newspaper [Pennsylvania evening herald]. For dup. see in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania...no.47.
  - Message to the assembly of Pennsylvania., 1758; 974.8 D65. 5; Pennsylvania (Colony) Governor - Denny, William
    2p. F. Phil. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 5.) Manuscript.
  - Proclamation for keeping the peace with the Indians., 1728; 974.8 D65. 7; Pennsylvania (Colony) - Governor - Gordon, Patrick
    2p. F. Phil. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 7.) Manuscript.
  - Proclamation for suppressing riots., 1729; 974.8 D65. 8; Pennsylvania (Colony) Governor - Gordon, Patrick
    2p. F. Phil. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 8.) Manuscript.
  - Proclamation relating to the commission to run the line between Pennsylvania and Delaware., 1738; 974.8 D65. 9; Pennsylvania (Colony) Governor - Thomas, George
    2p. F. Phil. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 9.) Manuscript.
  - Account of the capture of the General Monk by the Hyder Alley., Undated; 974.8 D65. 43; Mease, James, 1771-1846
    5p. F. n.p. 1825. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. no.43.)
  - Act of Parliament for opening commercial intercourse with the United States., Undated; 974.8 D65. 44; Great Britain. Parliament
    2p. F. n.p., n.d. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. no.44.) Manuscript copy.
  - Examination of Michael La Chauvignerie, jr., Undated; 974.8 D65. 15; Allen, William, 1704-1780
    a French prisoner, before Chief Justice Allen. 4p. F. n.p. 1757. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. no. 15) Manuscript.
  - From A Countryman to the Messers Bradford., Undated; 974.8 D65. 28; Bradford, William, 1719-1791
    2p. F. n.p., n.d. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. no.28) Manuscript.
  - From the Committee of correspondence of the province of Massachusetts Bay to the Committee of correspondence in the province of Pennsylvania., Undated; 974.8 D65. 33; Massachusetts (Colony) - Committee of correspondence.
    1 p. F. Boston, 1774. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. no.33) Manuscript.
  - Message to the assembly of Pennsylvania., Undated; 974.8 D65. 6; Pennsylvania (Colony) Governor - Hamilton, James.
    3p. F. n.p. 1762. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution. No. 6.) Manuscript.
  - Minute of a meeting of a committee of the West India planters and merchants., Undated; 974.8 D65. 46; West India Planters and Merchants (London, England)
    2p. F. n.p., n.d. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. No. 46.) Manuscript
  - Minute of a meeting of a committee of the West India planters and merchants., Undated; 974.8 D65. 45; West India Planters and Merchants (London, England)
    3p. F. n.p. 1784. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. No. 45) Manuscript.
  - Order of Capt. Desligneris, Undated; 974.8 D65. 13; Desligneris, Capt.
    Fort Duquesne. 1p. F. Fort Duquesne 1757. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American Revolution no.13.) Manuscripts.
  - Report to committee of the American philosophical society, Undated; 974.8 D65. 48; Pollock, James, 1810-1890
    giving a numerical statement of Continental troops engaged in the Revolution. 2p. F. Shepherdstown, Va. 1816. (in Documents relating to the province of Pennsylvania and to the American revolution. No. 48.) Manuscript.